A Guide to the Charles McDowell Papers, 1944-2004
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Charles McDowell Papers, 1944-2004
The Library of Virginia
44427
17 cubic feet (36 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ann McDowell, Alexandria.
Biographical Information
Charles Rice McDowell, Jr. was born in Danville, Kentucky on 24 June 1926. He is the son of Charles Rice McDowell, Sr. (1895-1968) and Catherine Frazier Feland (1904-1986). When he was young, the family moved to Lexington, Virginia, where the elder McDowell was a professor of law at Washington and Lee University. The younger McDowell was a student there, where he majored in English, and graduated in 1948. He then attended the Columbia University School of Journalism, and graduated the following year.
McDowell then moved to Richmond Virginia, and joined the staff of the Richmond Times-Dispatch, where he would remain his entire career, retiring in 1998. He covered local news, and was then assigned to the State Capitol, where he reported on the Virginia General Assembly and state politics. In 1954, McDowell began to write a syndicated column which appeared 3-4 times per week, and would span the remainder of his career. He was assigned to Washington, D.C. in 1965, and he relocated to Alexandria. McDowell wrote three books: "Campaign Fever," which was a journal of the 1964 presidential election, and two collections of humor columns entitled "One Thing After Another" (1960) and "What Did You Have in Mind?" (1963). He was also a panelist on PBS's "Washington Week in Review" for 18 years, beginning in 1978, and he was a writer, narrator, and host for other PBS programs, including "Summer of Judgement: The Watergate Hearings," "Richmond Memories," and "For the Record." McDowell also provided voice-overs for the productions "The Civil War" and "Baseball" by Ken Burns.
McDowell was inducted in the Virginia Communications Hall of Fame in 1988, and awarded the Fourth Estate Award by the National Press Club in 1996. He married Ann Rice of Ashland, Virginia. McDowell died on 5 November 2010.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1944-2004, of Charles McDowell (1926-2010) of Alexandria, Virginia, documenting his career as a reporter for the Richmond Times-Dispatch, panelist on the PBS program "Washington Week in Review," and other journalistic activities. Includes columns, correspondence and subject files, books, and videotapes.
Contents List
- Series I. Columns, 1946-1998., Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 1-9)
  The collection contains photocopies of McDowell's column which appeared in the Richmond Times-Dispatch from 1954 until his retirement in 1998. The columns appeared 3-4 times per week, and were also syndicated by Media General News Service and the Scripps Howard News Service and appeared in other newspapers across the country. The earliest columns were titled "Charles McDowell Today" and "Capital Sidelights." McDowell wrote on a wide variety of topics of local, state, and national interest, including politics, history, personal news, society and popular culture, weather, and sports. Recurring fictional characters appeared in the column over the many years it ran, namely McDowell's relative Aunt Gertrude, his neighbor Mr. Bumbleton, Reliable Source, and Alfred the Capitol Square Squirrel. McDowell's columns were laced with satirical musings and political punditry. There are no copies of the column for the years 1986 to 1997, but there is an index which includes the title of the column, paper in which it appeared, date, and page number. This series also includes early articles written by McDowell while he was a student at Washington and Lee University entitled "Reporter-at-Large," and as a sports reporter for the Roanoke Times entitled "Time For Sports."
  Chronological.
  - 3 November 1958-31 December 1962. (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
  - 1 January 1963-30 June 1966. (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
  - 1 July 1966-31 December 1970. (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
  - 1 January 1971-31 December 1973. (Box 4, Folder 1-12)
  - 1 January 1974-25 December 1977. (Box 5, Folder 1-13)
  - 1977-1980. (Box 6, Folder 1-13)
  - 1981-1998. (Box 7, Folder 1-12)
  - Columns - Editorial Page. (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
  - Columns - February, Seasons, Holidays. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Columns - Free Lance, 1950's. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Columns to Reprint (Maybe). (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Good Columns. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Op-Ed Columns, 1958-1959. (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Original Proposal for Column and Test Columns. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Roanoke Times Columns ("Time for Sports"). (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Sunday Columns, 1954-1959. (Box 8, Folder 10-13)
  - Sunday Columns, 1959. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Sunday Columns, 1960. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Washington and Lee Columns. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Series II. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1944-2004., Extent: 25 boxes. (Box 10-34)
  The correspondence contains letters written by readers of McDowell's column, and those who viewed his appearances on the PBS program "Washington Week in Review" and other programs. The correspondence includes reactions, both for and against, to McDowell's writings and viewpoints. There are also congratulatory letters relating to the many awards he received and upon his retirement in 1998, as well as invitations to make appearances and speeches, ideas for future columns, and resumes from prospective journalists. There is also correspondence between McDowell and literary agents and magazine editors.
  The subject files contain a wide variety of materials relating to McDowell's nearly 40 years as a journalist and author. There are manuscript drafts and free-lance articles for various publications, reviews, publicity, and correspondence relating to books he wrote, including "One Thing After Another" (1960), "What Did You Have in Mind?" (1963), and "Campaign Fever" (1965). There is background information for his articles, columns, and speeches, especially on the subjects of Congress, television and political conventions, elections, inaugurations, and campaign finance reform.
  McDowell did voice-overs for the Ken Burns productions, "The Civil War" (1990) and "Baseball" (1994), and the collection contains articles and reviews, notes, correspondence, clippings, and screening and final scripts. He also was a host on the program "For the Record," which aired on Central Virginia Public Television, which was devoted to public policy, politics, and history. The collection includes drafts of questions McDowell posed to his guests, working files, and background biographical information. Videotapes of some of the programs are also included in the collection. McDowell also a narrated the 1983 program on Watergate called, "Summer of Judgment: The Watergate Hearings," which was a production of WETA in Washington, DC. There are reviews, viewer mail, and a transcript of the program.
  The subject files also include biographical information, copies of his daily news articles and special feature stories for the Richmond Times-Dispatch, get well cards, Gridiron Club dinner programs, speeches, scripts, clippings, and membership lists, information on the visit of Nikita Khrushchev to the United States in 1959, photographs, programs, speech notes and drafts, as well as information relating to his work with Paul Duke (1926-2005), and with the Virginia congressional campaign of Andrew McCutcheon.
  Alphabetical.
  - Academy Road House. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Atlantic - Ideas, Correspondence, etc.. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Atlantic - New Hampshire Primary, 1967. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Atlantic - Television and the Convention, 1968. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic - Virginia Politics, 1969. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Automobile. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Baseball" by Ken Burns. (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
  - "Baseball" by Ken Burns - Final Script. (Box 10, Folder 10-12)
  - "Baseball" by Ken Burns - Screenings. (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - "Baseball" by Ken Burns - Screenings. (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Biographical Information, Citations, etc.. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Bolivia Trip, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Book Project - "One Thing After Another". (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Book Reviews. (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
  - Bourbon. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Mr. Bumbleton. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - "Campaign Fever" - Letters to Morrow. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - "Campaign Fever" - Reviews and Publicity. (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
  - Campaign Finance Material for Speeches. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Campaign Finance Reform. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Campaign Reform. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Capitol Building. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Census. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Center for the Book. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Certificates. (Box 35)
  - Chestnut Blight. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Cigarettes - Health. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cities. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Civil Rights. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - "The Civil War" by Ken Burns. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - "The Civil War" by Ken Burns - Reviews, Artifacts, etc.. (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
  - Civil War - Speech Notes. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Clinton and the Press, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Clinton Impeachment. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, Drafts, Notes, 2001. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Columbia School of Journalism 50th Class Reunion, 1999. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Congress, 89th. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Congress, 90th. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "The Congress" by Ken Burns, 1989. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Consular Treaty. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Conventions, 1952, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Conventions, 1960. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Conventions, 1968. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Conventions, 1984. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Conventions, 1996. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1989. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1990. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1991. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 13-16)
  - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 13, Folder 17-18)
  - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1994. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1998. (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999. (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 1999. (Box 14, Folder 8-11)
  - Correspondence, 2000. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2002. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2003-2004. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Agents, Magazines, etc.. (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
  - Crab Derby, 1962. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - D.A.R. Convention. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Daily Stories, 1950-1951. (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
  - Daily Stories, 1952. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Daily Stories, 1953. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Daily Stories #4, 1954-1957. (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
  - Danville (KY) Progress Report, 2001. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Debt Limit. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Democratic Convention, 1952. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Democratic Convention, 1968. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Democratic National Convention - Columns, 1956. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Democratic Primary, 1969. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Democrats - Virginia. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Dial - Twilight of a Presidency, 1984. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Drug Hearings, 1970. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Duke, Paul. (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
  - Eisenhower. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Elk (Bellwood). (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Ephraim McDowell Foundation. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Ethics. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Facts, Statistics, etc.. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Fairfax County - History, Geography, News, etc.. (Box 16, Folder 13-14)
  - Fat Albert (School Bus). (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Federal Grants - Virginia. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Fiction Project. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - File "X" (Notes, Family Material, Correspondence, etc.). (Box 16, Folder 18-20)
  - File "Y". (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Filibuster, 1965. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Finnegan the Fire Chief. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Fishback Lecture - Washington and Lee,. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Flamingo Column. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Flamingo Folklore. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Flugelman-606. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - "For the Record". (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - "For the Record" - Julian Bond. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "For the Record" - Lee Hamilton. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "For the Record" - Linwood Holton. (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
  - "For the Record" - Jim Jones (Bad Blood). (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - "For the Record" - Gale Mattox. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - "For the Record" - Bobby Muller. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - "For the Record" - Timothy Naftali. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "For the Record" - Kevin Phillips (The Cousins' Wars). (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - "For the Record" - John Sununu. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - "For the Record" - Kathryn Thornton. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - "For the Record" - Stansfield Turner. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - "For the Record" - Lech Walesa. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - "For the Record" - John Warner. (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - "For the Record" - Margaret Warner. (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - "For the Record" - Lowell Weicker. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "For the Record" - Philip Zelikow. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "For the Record" - Running File (Business, Planning, etc.). (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Fourth Estate Award - Speeches, Letters, Clips, 1996. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Henry Fowler. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Fowler, Henry. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Frazier, Emery L.. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Funny Stories for Speeches. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - General Assembly, 1952. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - General Motors and its Detective (Ralph Nader), 1966. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Get Well Letters, 1999. (Box 18, Folder 10-13)
  - Glaser, Lewis - Quill Pens. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Glassboro Summit, June 1967. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - G.O.P. - Chicago, 1952. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - G.O.P. Convention, 1996. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Gridiron Club Artifacts. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Gridiron Club Dinner, 1999. (Box 19, Folder 3-6)
  - Gridiron Club Dinner, 2000. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Gridiron Club Dinner, 2001. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Gridiron Club Dinner (and Hawaii Speech), 2002. (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - Gridiron Club Dinners, 2003-2004. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Gridiron Club 100th Anniversary, 1985. (Box 19, Folder 12-14)
  - Gridiron Club Photographs. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Gridiron Speeches (Reagan, Gore, Clinton, etc.). (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Gun Control Bill, 1968. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Hardy, Porter, Jr. (Member of Congress). (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Lecture, 16 December 1986. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Hawaii, 1997 (and earlier). (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Hawaii, 2000 (Cancelled). (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
  - Hawaii, 2001. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Hawaii, 2002. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Highways and Toll Roads. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Holton, Linwood. (Box 20, Folder 12-13)
  - Humor and Politics. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Hunger. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Hunting Creek Affair, 1968. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Huntley Meadows. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Inaugurations. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Inaugurations - PBS Documentary, 1992. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - "The James: Revolutionary River". (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B.. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Kennedy, Robert. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Khrushchev Trip to U.S., 1959. (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
  - Last Wagon West. (Box 21, Folder 8-9)
  - Lawyers Title News. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Letters To and From Congress. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Lexington. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Lexington (McCrum). (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - "Littlest Bunny" - Haynie and McDowell. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Magazine By-Lines. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Magazine Stories. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Mansfield, Mike. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts and Drafts. (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Markers. (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Martinsville Seven. (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Massive Resistance (Latimer History). (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - McCutcheon Campaign, 1968. (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - McDowell, Catherine. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Media General - Phone Directory. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Media General Washington Bureau (Doster Memos). (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Medicare. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Memorabilia. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Meredith, Henry. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Moon (Space Exploration). (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Morrow Correspondence - "Campaign Fever". (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Morrow Publicity. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - The Names People Elect, 1975. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - "New Towns" - WETA, 1986. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - News and Features, 1965-1966. (Box 22, Folder 14-15)
  - News and Features, 1967. (Box 22, Folder 16-17)
  - News and Features, 1968. (Box 22, Folder 18-19)
  - News and Features, 1969. (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - News and Features, 1970. (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
  - News and Features, January 1971-May 1972. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - News and Features, June-December 1972. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - News and Features, 1973. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - News and Features, 1974-1975. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - News and Features, 1976. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - News and Features Stories - Conventions, etc. 1970's. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - News-Leader Biographies. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Newsweek. (Box 23, Folder 12-13)
  - Newsweek Ad for "Washington Week in Review," 25 March 1991. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Nixon, Richard M.. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "No Higher Honor: Linwood Holton". (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Northern Virginia Politics. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Notes for President. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "Nuclear War: A Guide to Armageddon," 1982. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Numbers - Richmond and Hopewell (Gambling). (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Nuts (Publications, Mail, Organizations, etc.). (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity (OEO) - Sargent Shriver. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Old Speech Notes, 1961-1966. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Oliver Hill. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Outside Pieces - Free Lance. (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
  - "Packaging American Wars" - Roanoke TV, 1982. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Pennies and Dollar Coin. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Personal Artifacts, 1981-1985. (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
  - Personal Relics, etc.. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Photographs. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Plants. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Politicians (Speech Topic). (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Politics, 1960. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Politics, 1992. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Politics Poop. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Pollard, Fred G.. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Pollution - Ecology. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Post Reprints. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Poverty - Food Programs. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Powell, Lewis F.. (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - "Power Battle" Series, 1949. (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Power Companies - Utilities. (Box 25, Folder 18-19)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1968. (Box 25, Folder 20-21)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1968. (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - Presidential Campaign, 2000. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Presidential Campaign - Clippings, 2000. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Presidential Humor. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Press Conferences. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Press - Dinners 1968. (Box 26, Folder 7-8)
  - Press Passes. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Project - People's "Papers". (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - P.T.A.. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Public Broadcasting. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Public Housing Series, 1949. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Puns in Newspapers. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Puzzles. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Quotes and Anecdotes. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Racoons. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Rawlings, George C., Jr.. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Reagan, Ronald. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Reapportionment. (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Redistricting. (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Republican Convention, 1980. (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Republican Convention, 1988. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Republican Right. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Republicans - Virginia. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Retirement. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Retirement - Clippings. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Retirement, July 1998. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Richmond. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - "Richmond Memories". (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Newspaper Guild. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Roads. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Robb, Chuck - Clippings. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Robertson, A. Willis. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Rockwell, George Lincoln - Nazi. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Rogallo Kite. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Romney, George. (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Rural Virginia. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Sabato Analysis - 1994 U.S. Senate Election. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Safe Deposit Box. (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Satterfield, David E. III. (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Section IV Light. (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Section IV News Background. (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Selected Clips. (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Sigma Delta Chi. (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Smith, Howard W.. (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Smoking. (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Social Security. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Sold and Dead Pile. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Speech - "A Good Word for Politicians" - UVA, 1985. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Speech - Arizona Senior Academy, 2000. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Speech in the Dark, 1983. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Speech Material. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Speech Notes and Drafts, 1997-1998. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Speech Notes and Drafts, 2000-2001. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Speech Prep - Recent Texts, 1997-1999. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Speech Prep - Statistics, Quotes, Jokes, etc.. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Speech Schedule and Texts, 1998-2001. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Speeches, 1995. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Speeches, 1996-1997. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Speeches, 1998. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Speeches, 1999-2000. (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
  - Speeches, 2000-2001. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, 2001. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Spong, William B.. (Box 29, Folder 6-9)
  - State of the World Global Conference, 1993. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Stationary. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - "Summer of Judgment: The Watergate Hearings". (Box 29, Folder 12-13)
  - "Summer of Judgment: The Watergate Hearings" - Reviews, Mail. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - "Summer of Judgment: The Watergate Hearings" - Transcript. (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - Sunday Magazine. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Supreme Court. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Sympathy Letters - Death of Catherine F. McDowell, 1986. (Box 30, Folder 5-7)
  - Tax Cut Issue - Clippings, 1999. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Tax Sharing. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Television and Politics. (Box 30, Folder 10-12)
  - Thanksgiving. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Three Characters from Lexington. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Times-Dispatch and Television. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Tornado of 1951. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Train Wreck - R.F. & P., 1970. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Tuck, Gov. Bill. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Un-American Activities Committee. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Uncle Billy. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - VEPCO. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Veterans Administration. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Vice-President, 1968. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Vietnam. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Museum. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Politics. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Voting Rights. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Wallace, George C.. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Warren Commission. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Washington, D.C. - Tourism, Monuments, etc.. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - "Washington Week in Review" - Anniversaries. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - "Washington Week in Review" at 1992 Political Conventions. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - "Washington Week in Review" - Mail, 1982. (Box 32, Folder 1-5)
  - "Washington Week in Review" - Mail, 1987. (Box 32, Folder 6-12)
  - "Washington Week in Review" - Mail, 1989. (Box 33, Folder 1-7)
  - "Washington Week in Review" - Mail, 1990. (Box 33, Folder 8-11)
  - "Washington Week in Review" - Mail, 1992. (Box 33, Folder 12-13)
  - "Washington Week in Review" - Mail, 1992. (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
  - "Washington Week in Review" - Mail, 1995-1996. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Washingtonian - William C. Battle, 1969. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Washingtonian - Howell vs. Godwin, 1973. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Washingtonian - The Political History of Virginia, 1977. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Washingtonian - TV, Politics, 1986. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Washingtonian - Article of Charles McDowell, 2000. (Box 34, Folder 10)